Hey, how's it going?
Welcome to expert diving.
I'm Bobby Larew, your expert for the day.
We're talking about the jump, OK, in the hurdle, alright.
We've set ourself up, we've got our last step, our arms have come back, we're driving down in to the board, OK. We're going to push up, now we are actually ready to jump up in to the air, OK.
Jumping is a little tricky because as you jump, the board is flexing down, OK.
It's not solid ground, so you might feel a little weird bouncing on the end of the board.
But here's what the jump is actually going to look like.
You press down in to the board to get a little push and a little spring, then you're going to explode.
We worked on the leg strengthen exercises, here's where they come in to play.
Arms swing up, knee swings up, everything is driving up so that you can jump off of one foot as high as you possibly can jump.
And after you jump, you want to stretch, rise in to the air, OK, watch.
OK, that's the jump in diving.